export const COSTINGA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Cost that has already been incurred is",
A: "controllable cost.",
B: "Historical cost",
C: "imputed cost.",
D: "opportunity cost",
answer: "A. cost centres and cost units.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A purpose of cost accounting is to",
A: "control cost of operation.",
B: "determine sunk cost",
C: "determine the profitability of a business.",
D: "finance manufacturing operations",
answer: "A. control cost.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Cost which can be traced to a cost unit is",
A: "direct cost",
B: "fixed cost",
C: "indirect cost",
D: "period cost",
answer: "D. relevant for the intended purpose",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Grouping of costs as fixed or variable is classification by",
A: "behaviour",
B: "function",
C: "nature",
D: "verification",
answer: "C. simple.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The elements of cost of a product are",
A: "direct material, direct labour and direct expenses.",
B: "indirect material, indirect labour and indirect expenses.",
C: "material, labour and expenses.",
D: "material, labour and overheads.",
answer: "A. characteristics.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The sum of direct material cost, direct labour cost and production overheads is",
A: "conversion cost",
B: "prime cost.",
C: "production cost.",
D: "total expenses.",
answer: "C. prime cost.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following is not a stores record?",
A: "Bin card",
B: "Tally card",
C: "Stock ledger",
D: "Time sheet",
answer: "C. imputed cost.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following documents is a response by a supplier to a letter of enquiry?",
A: "Order",
B: "Quotation",
C: "Receipts",
D: "Waybill",
answer: "C. production cost.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. High material handling cost is associated with",
A: "large production.",
B: "ordering cost.",
C: "overstocking.",
D: "under stocking.",
answer: "B. loss of customers.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. ln times of rising prices, which of the following methods of pricing issues from stores result in higher profit?",
A: "FIFO method",
B: "LIFO method",
C: "simple average method",
D: "Weighted average method",
answer: "A. FIFO.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Using FIFO method of stock valuation, the cost of issue is",
A: "D15,750.",
B: "D15,500.",
C: "D14,750.",
D: "D14,000.",
answer: "C. GH¢ 14,750.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. What is the cost of issues using LIFO method of stock valuation?",
A: "D15,750",
B: "D15,500",
C: "D14,750",
D: "D14,000",
answer: "A.  GH¢ 15,750.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Using simple average method of stock valuation, the cost of closing stock is",
A: "D 6,750.",
B: "D 6,450.",
C: "D 6,375.",
D: "D 6,000",
answer: "B. GH¢ 6,450.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following is as statutory deduction from payroll?",
A: "Loan repayment",
B: "Provident fund",
C: "Staff contribution",
D: "Social security fund",
answer: "D. Social security fund",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Records used in accounting for labour include",
A: "clock card and bin card",
B: "stock sheet and time sheet",
C: "time card and bin card.",
D: "time card and job card.",
answer: "D. time card and job card.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The remuneration for direct labour is",
A: "bonus",
B: "overtime",
C: "salaries",
D: "wages",
answer: "D. wages",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. What is the employee’s basic pay?",
A: "D 2,300",
B: "D 2,100",
C: "D 2,000",
D: "D 1,900",
answer: "C.  D 2,000.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. What is the employee’s taxable income?",
A: "D 2,300",
B: "D 2,100.",
C: "D 2,000.",
D: "D 1,900.",
answer: "C.  D 2,000.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The gross salary of the employee is",
A: "D 2,300.",
B: "D 2,100.",
C: "D 2,000.",
D: "D 1,900.",
answer: "A.  D 2,300.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Power rating of machinery will be an appropriate basis of apportioning",
A: "canteen services",
B: "depreciation",
C: "electricity",
D: "rent.",
answer: "C. electricity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The basis for apportioning indirect material cost to department is",
A: "area occupied.",
B: "direct allocation.",
C: "labour hours worked.",
D: "number of employees",
answer: "A.  area occupied.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The charging of overheads to cost units is",
A: "absorption.",
B: "allocation.",
C: "allotment.",
D: "apportionment.",
answer: "A.  absorption.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Under and over-absorption of overheads arise due to the use of",
A: "absorption costing technique.",
B: "marginal costing technique.",
C: "predetermined absorption rates.",
D: "variable production overheads.",
answer: "C. predetermined absorption rates.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Labour hour overhead absorption rate is",
A: "Le 300 per hour.",
B: "Le 220 per hour",
C: "Le 150 per hour.",
D: "Le 120 per hour",
answer: "C. Le 150 per hour.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Machine hour overhead absorption rate is.",
A: "Le 300 per hour.",
B: "Le 220 per hour.",
C: "Le 150 per hour.",
D: "Le 120 per hour",
answer: "B. Le 220 per hour.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following is a costing method?",
A: "Absorption costing",
B: "Batch costing",
C: "Marginal costing",
D: "Standard costing",
answer: "C. Marginal costing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Process loss which is less than expected loss results in",
A: "abnormal gain",
B: "abnormal loss",
C: "normal loss",
D: "unexpected loss",
answer: "A. abnormal gain",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Job order costing is used by",
A: "chocolate manufacturers",
B: "crude oil refinery",
C: "flour manufacturers",
D: "textbook printers",
answer: "D. textbook printers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Contribution per unit is",
A: "sales minus total variable cost",
B: "selling price minus variable cost per unit",
C: "total cost minus fixed cost",
D: "total sales minus total cost",
answer: "B. selling price minus variable cost per unit",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Total cost of Job Z is",
A: "D 1,790",
B: "D 1,756",
C: "D 1,765",
D: "D 1,840",
answer: "A.  D 1,790",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. If Job Z is marked up at 20%, its selling price is",
A: "D 1,200.",
B: "D 1,750.",
C: "D 2,100.",
D: "D 2,208.",
answer: "C.  D 2,100.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. In marginal costing, fixed cost for a period is regarded as",
A: "marginal cost.",
B: "period cost.",
C: "product cost.",
D: "total cost",
answer: "B. period cost.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The difference between marginal costing and absorption costing is in the treatment of",
A: "fixed overheads.",
B: "material costs.",
C: "prime costs.",
D: "variable overheads",
answer: "A.  fixed overheads.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Contribution to sales ratio is",
A: "25.0%.",
B: "33.3%.",
C: "50.0%.",
D: "66.7%.",
answer: "B. 33.3%.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Break-even point in units is",
A: "200 units.",
B: "333 units.",
C: "500 units",
D: "1,000 units",
answer: "C. 500 units",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. A budget that estimates the quantity of goods to be manufactured is a",
A: "production budget.",
B: "production cost budget.",
C: "master budget.",
D: "sales budget",
answer: "A. production budget.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following is a limitation in budgeting?",
A: "It co-ordinating activities",
B: "It increases productivity",
C: "It is based on estimates",
D: "It serves as-motivational tool",
answer: "C. It is based on estimates",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Production budget is",
A: "85,000 units.",
B: "95,000 units.",
C: "105,000 units.",
D: "110,000 units",
answer: "A.  85,000 units.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Material usage budget is",
A: "255,000 kg.",
B: "285,000, kg.",
C: "315,000 kg.",
D: "330,000 kg.",
answer: "B. 285,000, kg.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Material purchase budget is",
A: "D 1,785,000",
B: "D 1,995,000",
C: "D 2,205,000",
D: "D 2,310,000",
answer: "D. D 2,310,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The objectives of preparing budgets are",
A: "distinguishing between master and functional budgets.",
B: "enhancing buying and selling",
C: "planning and control.",
D: "reducing and controlling costs",
answer: "C. planning and control.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. If the labour rate variance is GH¢3,600F and labour efficiency variance is GH¢2,80QA, the total labour cost variance is",
A: "GH¢ 6,400F.",
B: "GH¢ 800F.",
C: "GH¢ 800A.",
D: "GH¢ 6,400A.",
answer: "B. GH¢ 800F.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The technique used in evaluating deviations of actual from expected results is",
A: "absorption costing.",
B: "break-even analysis.",
C: "marginal costing.",
D: "variance analysis",
answer: "D. variance analysis",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A standard set for use over a long period of time is",
A: "ideal standard.",
B: "attainable standard.",
C: "basic standard.",
D: "current standard.",
answer: "B. basic standard.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Material cost variance may be analyzed into",
A: "efficiency and usage.",
B: "price and efficiency.",
C: "price and usage.",
D: "rate and efficiency",
answer: "B. price and efficiency.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Variance arising from actual productivity of workers being different from expected is labour",
A: "cost variance",
B: "efficiency variance",
C: "mix variance.",
D: "Rate variance.",
answer: "B. efficiency variance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Agreement between financial and costing profits is reached by preparing",
A: "bank reconciliation statement.",
B: "general ledger control account.",
C: "memorandum reconciliation statement",
D: "profit and loss adjustment account.",
answer: "C. memorandum reconciliation statement",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Depreciation charged in costing books D 1,600 and that charged in financial books is D 1,350. If costing profit is D 6,500 financial profit is",
A: "D 8,100.",
B: "D 7,850.",
C: "D 6,750.",
D: "D 6,250",
answer: "B. D 7,850.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The accounting entries for absorbing overheads into production are Debit.",
A: "Expenses Account; Credit-Work in Progress Control Account.",
B: "Production Over head Account; Credit Work in Progress Control Account.",
C: "Work in Progress Control Account; Credit Production Overhead Control Account.",
D: "Work in Progress Control Account; Credit Stores Account",
answer: "C. Work in Progress Control Account; Credit Production Overhead Control Account.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. One ledger kept in costing books",
A: "cash ledger.",
B: "purchase ledger.",
C: "sales ledger.",
D: "stores ledger",
answer: "D. stores ledger",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]